foreign
[Music]
my book how not to die was not about
living forever it was not how to not die
but rather how not to die as in
prematurely in pain after a long chronic
disabling illness the good news I shared
is that we have tremendous power over
our health Destiny and that the vast
majority of premature death and
disability is preventable with a healthy
enough diet lifestyle
how not to age has a similar premise
it's not about immortality but rather
how to age with Grace and vigor rather
than suffer from the ravages of
infirmity and decrepitude but why can't
we stop aging and live forever
from the Epic of gilgamesher four
thousand years ago to the recent
quincentennial Ponce De Leon's Pursuit
for the Fountain of Youth humankind has
yearned for the mythical elixir of life
that would remedy the scourges of aging
and why not it's not like aging some
immutable constant in nature
evolutionists produced lifespans in
animals that vary 5 000 full from those
only living a few days to clams clocking
in at over 500 years just like the
Wright brothers may have taken
inspiration from Birds we can take
inspiration from animals who age slower
if at all why can't we live forever some
animals do and I'm not talking about a
200 year old whale or even a
thousand-year-old tree I'm talking about
Immortal they're actually species with
names like the immortal jellyfish who
apparently don't age and could
technically go on forever and why not in
a sense humans are Immortal and that a
few of our cells live on sperm rag cells
lucky enough to find each other each of
our kids grow out of one of our cells
and that alone I mean the fact that a
single cell can grow into a person who
should make in comparison the notion of
keeping our bodies going indefinitely
seen biologically trivial one little
fertilized microscopic blob turning into
perhaps the most complex object in the
known universe the human brain
with its 86 billion neurons spanning a
hundred thousand miles within your head
like four times around the equator
making 150 trillion connections all
emerging out of a microscopic Speck of a
blob if that's possible in biology then
what isn't
still there's much skepticism in the
scientific Community where many believe
aging is an irreversible process
anti-aging is compared to being
anti-gravity
vocal critics in the gerontology
Community have accused those suggesting
the possibility of greatly extended the
human lifespans as being contemptible
for duping the public suggesting
anything bad to age 130 is ridiculous
such doubts are reliably countered by
proponents Who quote preeminent
scientists of your making similarly
absolutist claims that didn't
age well
Nobel prize-winning physicists spoke of
the prospect of nuclear power as talking
moonshine completely unscientific
utopian dream a childish Bugaboo Lord
Kelvin considered one of the greatest
scientists of his time notoriously
asserted heavier than air flying
machines are impossible evidently
doubling down on their impracticality In
1902 just a year before the first flight
at Kitty Hawk
already in the lab genetic mutation can
affect a tenfold increase in lifespan at
least in the species of tiny worm in
mice dietary and genetic manipulation
yields more like a 70 increase single
tweaks like methionine restriction which
is part of my anti-aging eight tips can
extend the average and maximum lifespan
of rats by about 40 percent which could
translate to boosting human lifespan to
an average of around 110 with a rare
centenarian hitting 140 these results
have yet to be replicated in people but
if we discovered intervention to not
only slow aging but actively repair the
accumulated damage to the sky could be
the limit
Starry Eyed scientists in the field
imagine time could be effectively melted
away like that surrealist painting of
drooping clocks a Rejuvenation of your
body leading ultimately to an Endless
Summer of literally Perpetual youth
a longevity escape velocity is envisage
in which we would just have to live long
enough for Innovations to add more time
than his passing the Tipping Point at
which each year we can add at least one
extra year of life expectancy this could
theoretically enable Humanity to have
essentially Unlimited lifespans
I remain agnostic as to whether such a
breakthrough as possible but I do hope
my new book will help regardless whether
you're striving to live long enough to
live forever or just trying to die young
as old as possible
[Music]
laughs
foreign